okay let's talk about design thinking
what does it mean what does design
thinking mean why is it so confusing why
is it so hard for people to get
we hear design thinking in the ux field
a lot is there some sort of magic
formula that designers do i want to
attempt to explain
what design thinking is how does it
actually work in the real world
well uh
design thinking is a human centered
approach to innovation it takes into
account
business people and technology
imagine the venn diagram three circles
you have your business
the viability of it the human side or
the people side
the desirability of it and then you have
the technical side
or the feasibility of it in the middle
is where innovation
comes i think this is still a bit too
complicated for people to really get
it's really just a problem-solving
framework okay
that's it so design thinking is actually
broken down into these
five phases so we have empathize is the
first really understanding the
context of the problem the problem space
and the second phase is define
basically clarifying what you want to
get out of this
and what problem you want to solve then
we have the third phase
idea the ideation phase is all about
creating a lot of solutions it's more
about quantity over quality
so here it allows us to explore and
experiment
and the fourth phase prototype once we
figured out
a potential solution for that problem we
can really start to build
representation of what that would look
like right how it's going to work in the
real world
then the final phase is test does it
work does it not work how can we improve
it is it the wrong idea
and then we can go back to the drawing
board the great thing about design
thinking is concept
is that it gives you sort of a mental
model to tackle real world problems
because it helps you put a framework to
problem solving it's not really
specific to designers developers people
in the software industry
it's an invaluable asset in my life and
i will
implore you guys to try it bruce my food
is nearly here